<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="temperature_facts">
        <item>
            FAHRENHEIT|Fahrenheit bases the boiling point of water at
            212 and the freezing point at 32. Developed by German-born Daniel Gabriel Fahrenheit
            in 1714, used primarily in the United States and some Caribbean countries.
        </item>
        <item>
            CELSIUS|Celsius represents the freezing point of water at 0 degrees, and 100 degrees
            represents water’s boiling point at the standard atmosphere, which is the mean
            barometric pressure at the mean sea level. Developed by Swedish astronomer Andres Celsius
            in 1742.
        </item>
        <item>
            KELVIN|Kelvin represents the freezing point of water at 273.16 kelvins
            and boiling point at 373.16 kelvins. Created by British scientist William Thomson in 1848,
            Kelvin is mostly used in scientific applications because of the lack of negative numbers,
            so it makes it easier to calculate very low temperatures of liquid helium and liquid nitrogen,
            for example.
        </item>
        <item>
            RANKINE|Rankine represents the freezing point of water at 491.67°Ra and boiling point at
            671.67°Ra. Created by Scottish engineer and physicist William Rankine in 1859.
        </item>
        <item>REAUMUR|Reaumur represennts the freezing point of water at 0°Ré and boiling point at
            80°Ré. It was invented by French physicist Rene Antoine de Reaumur around 1730.
            This scale is mostly used today in the measuring of milk temperature in cheese production,
            and when cooking sugar syrup for desserts and sweets.
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="temperature_fun_fact">
        Rumor has it that the hottest man-made temperature is 4 trillion degrees Celsius. That\'s
        250,000 times hotter than the center of the sun. Say what?!
    </string>

    <string-array name="area_facts">

    </string-array>
    <string name="area_fun_fact">
        Among all the shapes with the same perimeter a circle has the largest area.
    </string>

    <string-array name="length_facts">

    </string-array>
    <string name="length_fun_fact">
        The Great Wall of China is approximately 6,430 Km long (3,995 miles).
    </string>

    <string-array name="time_facts">

    </string-array>
    <string name="time_fun_fact">
        The longest recorded flight of a chicken was 13 seconds.
    </string>

    <string-array name="volume_facts">

    </string-array>
    <string name="volume_fun_fact">
        650 cubic centimetres is about as many grains of flour as people on the planet (7 billion).
    </string>

    <string-array name="weight_facts">

    </string-array>
    <string name="weight_fun_fact">
        Due to gravitational effects your weight is slightly less when the moon is directly overhead.
    </string>

</resources>
