<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="temperature_facts">
        <item>
            FAHRENHEIT|Fahrenheit bases the boiling point of water at
            212 and the freezing point at 32. Developed by German-born Daniel Gabriel Fahrenheit
            in 1714, used primarily in the United States and some Caribbean countries.
        </item>
        <item>
            CELSIUS|Celsius represents the freezing point of water at 0 degrees, and 100 degrees
            represents water’s boiling point at the standard atmosphere, which is the mean
            barometric pressure at the mean sea level. Developed by Swedish astronomer Andres Celsius
            in 1742.
        </item>
        <item>
            KELVIN|Kelvin represents the freezing point of water at 273.16 kelvins
            and boiling point at 373.16 kelvins. Created by British scientist William Thomson in 1848,
            Kelvin is mostly used in scientific applications because of the lack of negative numbers,
            so it makes it easier to calculate very low temperatures of liquid helium and liquid nitrogen,
            for example.
        </item>
        <item>
            RANKINE|Rankine represents the freezing point of water at 491.67°Ra and boiling point at
            671.67°Ra. Created by Scottish engineer and physicist William Rankine in 1859.
        </item>
        <item>
            REAUMUR|Reaumur represennts the freezing point of water at 0°Ré and boiling point at
            80°Ré. It was invented by French physicist Rene Antoine de Reaumur around 1730.
            This scale is mostly used today in the measuring of milk temperature in cheese production,
            and when cooking sugar syrup for desserts and sweets.
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="temperature_fun_fact">
        Rumor has it that the hottest man-made temperature is 4 trillion degrees Celsius. That\'s
        250,000 times hotter than the center of the sun. Say what?!
    </string>

    <string-array name="area_facts">
        <item>
            ACRE|The word acre is derived from Old English aecer originally meaning \"open field\".
            The acre was approximately the amount of land tillable by a yoke of oxen in one day.
            Statutory values for the acre were enacted in England by acts of Edward I,
            Edward III, Henry VIII, George IV and Queen Victoria.
        </item>
        <item>
            ARE|An are is a derived metric SI (System International) measurement unit of area
            used to measure land with sides equal to ten meters (10m). Its multiple, the hectare is
            the principal unit of land measurement for most of the world.
        </item>
        <item>
            BARN|Barn, unit of area used to measure the reaction cross section (generally different
            from the geometric cross section) of atomic nuclei and subatomic particles in the study
            of their interactions with other nuclei or particles. It is equal to 10−24 square cm.
            The name, coined by U.S. scientists, is derived from the proverbial phrase
            “side of a barn,” something easy to hit.
        </item>
        <item>
            HECTARE|Hectare, unit of area in the metric system equal to 100 ares, or 10,000 square
            metres, and the equivalent of 2.471 acres in the British Imperial System and the
            United States Customary measure. The term is derived from the Latin area and from hect,
            an irregular contraction of the Greek word for hundred. Although the are is the primary
            metric unit of land measurement, in practice the hectare is more commonly used.
        </item>
        <item>
            ROOD|The rood was an important measure in surveying on account of its easy conversion
            to acres. When referring to areas, rod is often found in old documents and has exactly
            the same meaning as rood.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREROD|Rod is an old English measure of distance equal to 16.5 feet,
            with variations from 9 to 28 feet also being used. The word rod
            derives from Old English rodd and is akin to Old Norse rudda (“club”).
            Rod is also akin to the Dutch rood which referred to a land area of 40 square rods,
            equal to one-quarter acre, or 10,890 square feet.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREFOOT|Foot, plural feet, in measurement, any of numerous ancient, medieval, and modern
            linear measures (commonly 25 to 34 cm) based on the length of the human foot and used
            exclusively in English-speaking countries, where it generally consists of 12 inches or
            one-third yard. In most countries and in all scientific applications, the foot
            has been superseded by the metre. In the United States the definition of the foot as exactly 30.48
            cm took effect in 1959.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREINCH|An inch is a unit of length in the imperial and United States customary
            systems of measurement. Sorry...that\'s all we got right now lol
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREMETER|The metre was historically defined by the French Academy of Sciences in 1791 as
            1/10,000,000 of the quadrant of the Earth\'s circumference running from the North Pole
            through Paris to the equator. Due to advances in laser measurement techniques, values for
            the speed of light in a vacuum were determined with unprecedented accuracy and it was then
            decided in 1983 by the General Conference on Weights and Measures that the accepted value
            for this constant would be exactly 299,792,458 metres per second. The metre is now thus
            defined as the distance traveled by light in a vacuum in 1/299,792,458 of a second.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREMILE|The mile originated from the Roman mille passus, or \"thousand paces\", which
            measured 5,000 Roman feet. A nautical mile was originally defined as the length on the Earth\'s surface
            of one minute of arc along a meridian (north-south line of longitude).
            In 1929 the nautical mile was redefined to 1.852 km at an international conference held in Monaco,
            since measurements differed due to a slight flattening of the Earth in the polar latitudes.
            The United States didn\'t change to the new measurement until 1954.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREYARD|Yard, Unit of length equal to 36 inches, or 3 feet (see foot), in the U.S. Customary
            System or 0.9144 metre in the International System of Units. A cloth yard, used to measure
            cloth, is 37 in. long; it was also the standard length for arrows. In casual speech, a
            yard (e.g., of concrete, gravel, or topsoil) may refer to a cubic yard.
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="area_fun_fact">
        Among all the shapes with the same perimeter a circle has the largest area.
    </string>

    <string-array name="length_facts">
        <item>
            INCHES|An inch is a unit of length in the imperial and United States customary
            systems of measurement. Sorry...that\'s all we got right now lol
        </item>
        <item>
            CENTIMETERS|A fingernail is about one centimeter wide. A centimetre or centimeter is a
            unit of length in the metric system, equal to one hundredth of a metre, centi being the
            SI prefix for a factor of ⁄100.
        </item>
        <item>
            MILLIMETERS|A millimeter is about the thickness of a plastic id card (or credit card).
            The millimetre or millimeter is a unit of length in the metric system, equal to one
            thousandth of a metre, which is the SI base unit of length.
        </item>
        <item>
            FEET|Foot, plural feet, in measurement, any of numerous ancient, medieval, and modern
            linear measures (commonly 25 to 34 cm) based on the length of the human foot and used
            exclusively in English-speaking countries, where it generally consists of 12 inches or
            one-third yard. In most countries and in all scientific applications, the foot
            has been superseded by the metre. In the United States the definition of the foot as exactly 30.48
            cm took effect in 1959.
        </item>
        <item>
            YARD|Yard, Unit of length equal to 36 inches, or 3 feet (see foot), in the U.S. Customary
            System or 0.9144 metre in the International System of Units. A cloth yard, used to measure
            cloth, is 37 in. long; it was also the standard length for arrows. In casual speech, a
            yard (e.g., of concrete, gravel, or topsoil) may refer to a cubic yard.
        </item>
        <item>
            METERS|The metre was historically defined by the French Academy of Sciences in 1791 as
            1/10,000,000 of the quadrant of the Earth\'s circumference running from the North Pole
            through Paris to the equator. Due to advances in laser measurement techniques, values for
            the speed of light in a vacuum were determined with unprecedented accuracy and it was then
            decided in 1983 by the General Conference on Weights and Measures that the accepted value
            for this constant would be exactly 299,792,458 metres per second. The metre is now thus
            defined as the distance traveled by light in a vacuum in 1/299,792,458 of a second.
        </item>
        <item>
            MILES|The mile originated from the Roman mille passus, or \"thousand paces\", which
            measured 5,000 Roman feet. A nautical mile was originally defined as the length on the Earth\'s surface
            of one minute of arc along a meridian (north-south line of longitude).
            In 1929 the nautical mile was redefined to 1.852 km at an international conference held in Monaco,
            since measurements differed due to a slight flattening of the Earth in the polar latitudes.
            The United States didn\'t change to the new measurement until 1954.
        </item>
        <item>
            KILOMETERS|Uhm...not much to say here. I guess whenever you want to measure really really really
            long lengths or distances you should use kilometers instead meters :)
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="length_fun_fact">
        The Great Wall of China is approximately 6,430 Km long (3,995 miles).
        A wall that long could cover the United States from east to west coast almost twice.
    </string>

    <string-array name="time_facts">
        <item>
            HOUR|Good question...why is an hour 60 minutes? Why 60? Why is a day 24 hours? Hmm.
            The Sumerians figured out 360 degree circles
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="time_fun_fact">
        The longest recorded flight of a chicken was 13 seconds.
    </string>

    <string-array name="volume_facts">
        <item>
            CUBICMETER|The metre was historically defined by the French Academy of Sciences in 1791 as
            1/10,000,000 of the quadrant of the Earth\'s circumference running from the North Pole
            through Paris to the equator. Due to advances in laser measurement techniques, values for
            the speed of light in a vacuum were determined with unprecedented accuracy and it was then
            decided in 1983 by the General Conference on Weights and Measures that the accepted value
            for this constant would be exactly 299,792,458 metres per second. The metre is now thus
            defined as the distance traveled by light in a vacuum in 1/299,792,458 of a second.
        </item>
        <item>
            CUBICINCH|An inch is a unit of length in the imperial and United States customary
            systems of measurement. Sorry...that\'s all we got right now lol
        </item>
        <item>
            CUBICYARD|Yard, Unit of length equal to 36 inches, or 3 feet (see foot), in the U.S. Customary
            System or 0.9144 metre in the International System of Units. A cloth yard, used to measure
            cloth, is 37 in. long; it was also the standard length for arrows. In casual speech, a
            yard (e.g., of concrete, gravel, or topsoil) may refer to a cubic yard.
        </item>
        <item>
            CUBICFOOT|Foot, plural feet, in measurement, any of numerous ancient, medieval, and modern
            linear measures (commonly 25 to 34 cm) based on the length of the human foot and used
            exclusively in English-speaking countries, where it generally consists of 12 inches or
            one-third yard. In most countries and in all scientific applications, the foot
            has been superseded by the metre. In the United States the definition of the foot as exactly 30.48
            cm took effect in 1959.
        </item>
        <item>
            LITER|From 1901 to 1964 the litre was defined as the volume of one kilogram of pure water at
            4 °C (39.2 °F) and standard atmospheric pressure; in 1964 the original present value was reinstated.
        </item>
        <item>
            GALLON|The gallon is a measure of liquid capacity in both the US customary units and the
            British imperial systems of measurement. It originated as the base of systems for measuring
            wine, and beer in England. The term derives most immediately from galun, galon in Old
            Northern French, but the usage was common in several languages, for example jale in Old
            French and gęllet (bowl) in Old English.
        </item>
        <item>
            USFLUIDOUNCE|The fluid ounce was originally the volume occupied by one ounce of some
            substance such as wine (in England) or water (in Scotland).
        </item>
        <item>
            USPINT|
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="volume_fun_fact">
        The Eiffel Tower can be 15cm taller during the summer due to thermal expansion, where particles
        move more thus taking up a larger volume.
    </string>

    <string-array name="weight_facts">

    </string-array>
    <string name="weight_fun_fact">
        Due to gravitational effects your weight is slightly less when the moon is directly overhead.
    </string>

</resources>
