<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="temperature_facts">
        <item>
            FAHRENHEIT|Fahrenheit bases the boiling point of water at
            212 and the freezing point at 32. Developed by German-born Daniel Gabriel Fahrenheit
            in 1714, used primarily in the United States and some Caribbean countries.
        </item>
        <item>
            CELSIUS|Celsius represents the freezing point of water at 0 degrees, and 100 degrees
            represents water’s boiling point at the standard atmosphere, which is the mean
            barometric pressure at the mean sea level. Developed by Swedish astronomer Andres Celsius
            in 1742.
        </item>
        <item>
            KELVIN|Kelvin represents the freezing point of water at 273.16 kelvins
            and boiling point at 373.16 kelvins. Created by British scientist William Thomson in 1848,
            Kelvin is mostly used in scientific applications because of the lack of negative numbers,
            so it makes it easier to calculate very low temperatures of liquid helium and liquid nitrogen,
            for example.
        </item>
        <item>
            RANKINE|Rankine represents the freezing point of water at 491.67°Ra and boiling point at
            671.67°Ra. Created by Scottish engineer and physicist William Rankine in 1859.
        </item>
        <item>
            REAUMUR|Reaumur represents the freezing point of water at 0°Ré and boiling point at
            80°Ré. It was invented by French physicist Rene Antoine de Reaumur around 1730.
            This scale is mostly used today in the measuring of milk temperature in cheese production,
            and when cooking sugar syrup for desserts and sweets.
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="temperature_fun_fact">
        Rumor has it that the hottest man-made temperature is 4 trillion degrees Celsius. That\'s
        250,000 times hotter than the center of the sun. Say what?!
    </string>

    <string-array name="area_facts">
        <item>
            ACRE|The word acre is derived from Old English aecer originally meaning \"open field\".
            The acre was approximately the amount of land tillable by a yoke of oxen in one day.
            Statutory values for the acre were enacted in England by acts of Edward I,
            Edward III, Henry VIII, George IV and Queen Victoria.
        </item>
        <item>
            ARE|An are is a derived metric SI (System International) measurement unit of area
            used to measure land with sides equal to ten meters (10m). Its multiple, the hectare is
            the principal unit of land measurement for most of the world.
        </item>
        <item>
            BARN|Barn, unit of area used to measure the reaction cross section (generally different
            from the geometric cross section) of atomic nuclei and subatomic particles in the study
            of their interactions with other nuclei or particles. It is equal to 10−24 square cm.
            The name, coined by U.S. scientists, is derived from the proverbial phrase
            “side of a barn,” something easy to hit.
        </item>
        <item>
            HECTARE|Hectare, unit of area in the metric system equal to 100 ares, or 10,000 square
            metres, and the equivalent of 2.471 acres in the British Imperial System and the
            United States Customary measure. The term is derived from the Latin area and from hect,
            an irregular contraction of the Greek word for hundred. Although the are is the primary
            metric unit of land measurement, in practice the hectare is more commonly used.
        </item>
        <item>
            ROOD|The rood was an important measure in surveying on account of its easy conversion
            to acres. When referring to areas, rod is often found in old documents and has exactly
            the same meaning as rood.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREROD|Rod is an old English measure of distance equal to 16.5 feet,
            with variations from 9 to 28 feet also being used. The word rod
            derives from Old English rodd and is akin to Old Norse rudda (“club”).
            Rod is also akin to the Dutch rood which referred to a land area of 40 square rods,
            equal to one-quarter acre, or 10,890 square feet.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREFOOT|Foot, plural feet, in measurement, any of numerous ancient, medieval, and modern
            linear measures (commonly 25 to 34 cm) based on the length of the human foot and used
            exclusively in English-speaking countries, where it generally consists of 12 inches or
            one-third yard. In most countries and in all scientific applications, the foot
            has been superseded by the metre. In the United States the definition of the foot as exactly 30.48
            cm took effect in 1959.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREINCH|An inch is a unit of length in the imperial and United States customary
            systems of measurement. The earliest known reference to the inch in England is from the
            Laws of Æthelberht dating to the early 7th century, surviving in a single manuscript
            from 1120. The English word inch comes from Latin uncia meaning "one-twelfth part", in this
            case one twelfth of a foot. In many other European languages, the word for "inch" is
            the same as or derived from the word for "thumb", as a man\'s thumb is about an inch wide.
            Although the inch was used in a number of other systems of units, today the international
            inch has been exactly defined as 25.4 millimetres. There are 12 inches in a foot and 36
            inches in a yard.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREMETER|The metre was historically defined by the French Academy of Sciences in 1791 as
            1/10,000,000 of the quadrant of the Earth\'s circumference running from the North Pole
            through Paris to the equator. Due to advances in laser measurement techniques, values for
            the speed of light in a vacuum were determined with unprecedented accuracy and it was then
            decided in 1983 by the General Conference on Weights and Measures that the accepted value
            for this constant would be exactly 299,792,458 metres per second. The metre is now thus
            defined as the distance traveled by light in a vacuum in 1/299,792,458 of a second.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREMILE|The mile originated from the Roman mille passus, or \"thousand paces\", which
            measured 5,000 Roman feet. A nautical mile was originally defined as the length on the Earth\'s surface
            of one minute of arc along a meridian (north-south line of longitude).
            In 1929 the nautical mile was redefined to 1.852 km at an international conference held in Monaco,
            since measurements differed due to a slight flattening of the Earth in the polar latitudes.
            The United States didn\'t change to the new measurement until 1954.
        </item>
        <item>
            SQUAREYARD|Yard, Unit of length equal to 36 inches, or 3 feet (see foot), in the U.S. Customary
            System or 0.9144 metre in the International System of Units. A cloth yard, used to measure
            cloth, is 37 in. long; it was also the standard length for arrows. In casual speech, a
            yard (e.g., of concrete, gravel, or topsoil) may refer to a cubic yard.
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="area_fun_fact">
        Among all the shapes with the same perimeter a circle has the largest area.
    </string>

    <string-array name="length_facts">
        <item>
            INCHES|An inch is a unit of length in the imperial and United States customary
            systems of measurement. The earliest known reference to the inch in England is from the
            Laws of Æthelberht dating to the early 7th century, surviving in a single manuscript
            from 1120. The English word inch comes from Latin uncia meaning "one-twelfth part", in this
            case one twelfth of a foot. In many other European languages, the word for "inch" is
            the same as or derived from the word for "thumb", as a man\'s thumb is about an inch wide.
            Although the inch was used in a number of other systems of units, today the international
            inch has been exactly defined as 25.4 millimetres. There are 12 inches in a foot and 36
            inches in a yard.
        </item>
        <item>
            CENTIMETERS|A fingernail is about one centimeter wide. A centimetre or centimeter is a
            unit of length in the metric system, equal to one hundredth of a metre, centi being the
            SI prefix for a factor of ⁄100.
        </item>
        <item>
            MILLIMETERS|A millimeter is about the thickness of a plastic id card (or credit card).
            The millimetre or millimeter is a unit of length in the metric system, equal to one
            thousandth of a metre, which is the SI base unit of length.
        </item>
        <item>
            FEET|Foot, plural feet, in measurement, any of numerous ancient, medieval, and modern
            linear measures (commonly 25 to 34 cm) based on the length of the human foot and used
            exclusively in English-speaking countries, where it generally consists of 12 inches or
            one-third yard. In most countries and in all scientific applications, the foot
            has been superseded by the metre. In the United States the definition of the foot as exactly 30.48
            cm took effect in 1959.
        </item>
        <item>
            YARDS|Yard, Unit of length equal to 36 inches, or 3 feet (see foot), in the U.S. Customary
            System or 0.9144 metre in the International System of Units. A cloth yard, used to measure
            cloth, is 37 in. long; it was also the standard length for arrows. In casual speech, a
            yard (e.g., of concrete, gravel, or topsoil) may refer to a cubic yard.
        </item>
        <item>
            METERS|The metre was historically defined by the French Academy of Sciences in 1791 as
            1/10,000,000 of the quadrant of the Earth\'s circumference running from the North Pole
            through Paris to the equator. Due to advances in laser measurement techniques, values for
            the speed of light in a vacuum were determined with unprecedented accuracy and it was then
            decided in 1983 by the General Conference on Weights and Measures that the accepted value
            for this constant would be exactly 299,792,458 metres per second. The metre is now thus
            defined as the distance traveled by light in a vacuum in 1/299,792,458 of a second.
        </item>
        <item>
            MILES|The mile originated from the Roman mille passus, or \"thousand paces\", which
            measured 5,000 Roman feet. A nautical mile was originally defined as the length on the Earth\'s surface
            of one minute of arc along a meridian (north-south line of longitude).
            In 1929 the nautical mile was redefined to 1.852 km at an international conference held in Monaco,
            since measurements differed due to a slight flattening of the Earth in the polar latitudes.
            The United States didn\'t change to the new measurement until 1954.
        </item>
        <item>
            KILOMETERS|Kilometers? Uhm...not much to say here. I guess whenever you want to measure really really really
            long lengths or distances you should use kilometers instead meters :)
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="length_fun_fact">
        The Great Wall of China is approximately 21,195.008 Kilometers long (13,170 Miles).
        A wall that long could stretch across the United States coats to coast over 4 times.
    </string>

    <string-array name="time_facts">
        <item>
            HOURS|The hour is a unit measurement of time where, in modern age, an hour comprises 60
            minutes, or 3,600 seconds. It is approximately 1/24 of a mean solar day. An hour in the
            UTC time standard can include a negative or positive leap second, and may therefore have
            a duration of 3,599 or 3,601 seconds for adjustment purposes. The division of time is traced
            back to the ancient Sumerians in the 4th millennium B.C. The Sumerians used the sexagesimal notation,
            which is a mathematical system based on groups of 60. The Egyptians later took advantage
            of this system to divide night and day into 12 equal hours.
        </item>
        <item>
            SECONDS|The second is defined as the second division of the hour by sixty, the first division
            by sixty being the minute. The second emerged from the necessity of devising an
            early geographic system that started with the latitude by the Greek astronomer Erathosthenes. A century later,
            Hipparchus devised a system of longitude that encompassed to run from north to south (pole to pole).
            Continuing his work, Ptolemy subdivided each of the 360 degrees of latitude and longitude
            into smaller segments. With first division being called minute, the second became known as
            second. Seconds weren\'t used until many centuries after Ptolemy\'s treatise of Almagest (circa A.D. 150).
        </item>
        <item>
            MINUTES|The minute is defined as the first division by sixty of the hour. Before the second,
            the minute was resultant from Ptolemy\'s explanation of Hipparchus\' geographic system of longitude.
            In his treatise of Almagest (circa A.D. 150) Ptolemy sought to explain and expand on the work of Hipparchus by
            In his treatise of Almagest (circa A.D. 150) Ptolemy sought to explain and expand on the work of Hipparchus by
            further subdividing each of the 360 degrees of latitude (introduced by GReek astronomer Erathosthenes) and longitude
            into smaller parts. Each degree was divided into 60 parts, each of which was again subdivided by 60. The
            first division was called \"partes minutae primae\" or first minute. The minute was not used in the clock
            system until many centuries later.
        </item>
        <item>
            DAYS|A day is an interval equal to 24 hours. It can also mean the consecutive period of time
            during which the Sun is above the horizon. It is the period of time during which the Earth completes
            one rotation around its axis, with respect to the Sun. Based on the definition of second, a day is 86 400 seconds.
            The term comes from Old English dæg, with its cognates such as dagur in Icelandic, Tag in German,
            and dag in Norwegian, Danish, Swedish and Dutch. The Earth\'s day has increased in length over time.
            This phenomenon is due to tides raised by the Moon which slow Earth\'s rotation. Because of
            the way the second is defined, the mean length of a day is now about 86 400.002 seconds,
            and is increasing by about 1.7 milliseconds per century (an average over the last 2 700 years).
        </item>
        <item>
            WEEKS|A week is a time unit equal to 7 days. It is the standard time period used for cycles
            of work days and rest days in most parts of the world, mostly alongside the Gregorian calendar.
            The 7 day period was derived from the Babylonian lunar months where the seven days were 1/4 of
            a month long. The naming of the days come from different languages and were associated with
            classical planets, deities, etc... Sunday - Sun\'s day, Monday - Moon\'s day, Tuesday - Tiu\'s day (Germanic god of war),
            Wednesday - Woden\'s day (chief Anglo-Saxon/Teutonic god), Thursday - Thor\'s day (Norse god of thunder),
            Friday - Freya\'s day (Teutonic goddess of love) and Saturday - Saturn\'s day (Roman god of agriculture).
        </item>
        <item>
            MONTHS|The concept of month arose with the cycle of moon phases. A phase of the moon is the shape of
            the illuminated portion of the Moon as seen by an observer on Earth. Julius Caesar\'s astronomers
            used this to explain the need for 12 months in a year and the addition of a leap year to synchronize with
            the seasons. At the time there were only 10 months in the calendar, and so the months of January
            and February were added to the calendar, where the original 5th and 6th months were changed to
            July and August to honour Julius and Augustus, his successor.
        </item>
        <item>
            YEARS|A year is the time it takes for the Earth to orbit around the Sun. Because of the Earth\'s
            axial tilt, a year is made up of passing seasons with changes in weather. A common year has 365
            days, whereas a leap year is 366 days long. Leap years occur every 4 years with the purpose of
            synchronizing the calendar year with the solar year, or the actual length of time it takes the earth to
            complete its orbit around the sun (~ 365 1/4 days). So by adding an extra day every 4 years,
            we ensure that the Earth is in the same point of its orbit at the same time of the calendar year,
            each year.
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="time_fun_fact">
        The longest recorded flight of a chicken was 13 seconds.
    </string>

    <string-array name="volume_facts">
        <item>
            CUBICMETER|The metre was historically defined by the French Academy of Sciences in 1791 as
            1/10,000,000 of the quadrant of the Earth\'s circumference running from the North Pole
            through Paris to the equator. Due to advances in laser measurement techniques, values for
            the speed of light in a vacuum were determined with unprecedented accuracy and it was then
            decided in 1983 by the General Conference on Weights and Measures that the accepted value
            for this constant would be exactly 299,792,458 metres per second. The metre is now thus
            defined as the distance traveled by light in a vacuum in 1/299,792,458 of a second.
        </item>
        <item>
            CUBICINCH|An inch is a unit of length in the imperial and United States customary
            systems of measurement. The earliest known reference to the inch in England is from the
            Laws of Æthelberht dating to the early 7th century, surviving in a single manuscript
            from 1120. The English word inch comes from Latin uncia meaning "one-twelfth part", in this
            case one twelfth of a foot. In many other European languages, the word for "inch" is
            the same as or derived from the word for "thumb", as a man\'s thumb is about an inch wide.
            Although the inch was used in a number of other systems of units, today the international
            inch has been exactly defined as 25.4 millimetres. There are 12 inches in a foot and 36
            inches in a yard.
        </item>
        <item>
            CUBICYARD|Yard, Unit of length equal to 36 inches, or 3 feet (see foot), in the U.S. Customary
            System or 0.9144 metre in the International System of Units. A cloth yard, used to measure
            cloth, is 37 in. long; it was also the standard length for arrows. In casual speech, a
            yard (e.g., of concrete, gravel, or topsoil) may refer to a cubic yard.
        </item>
        <item>
            CUBICFOOT|Foot, plural feet, in measurement, any of numerous ancient, medieval, and modern
            linear measures (commonly 25 to 34 cm) based on the length of the human foot and used
            exclusively in English-speaking countries, where it generally consists of 12 inches or
            one-third yard. In most countries and in all scientific applications, the foot
            has been superseded by the metre. In the United States the definition of the foot as exactly 30.48
            cm took effect in 1959.
        </item>
        <item>
            LITER|From 1901 to 1964 the litre was defined as the volume of one kilogram of pure water at
            4 °C (39.2 °F) and standard atmospheric pressure; in 1964 the original present value was reinstated.
        </item>
        <item>
            GALLON|The gallon is a measure of liquid capacity in both the US customary units and the
            British imperial systems of measurement. It originated as the base of systems for measuring
            wine, and beer in England. The term derives most immediately from galun, galon in Old
            Northern French, but the usage was common in several languages, for example jale in Old
            French and gęllet (bowl) in Old English.
        </item>
        <item>
            USFLUIDOUNCE|A fluid ounce is a unit of volume typically used for measuring liquids.
            It was originally the volume occupied by one ounce of some substance such as wine (in
            England) or water (in Scotland). In 1824, the British Parliament defined the imperial
            gallon as the volume of ten pounds of water. The US fluid ounce is based on the US gallon,
            which is based on the wine gallon of 231 cubic inches, used in England prior to 1824.
            With the adoption of the international inch the US fluid ounce became 29.5735295625 ml exactly.
        </item>
        <item>
            USPINT|The pint is a unit of volume or capacity in both the United States customary and
            British imperial measurement systems. In both of those systems it is traditionally
            one-eighth of a gallon. The British pint is about 20% larger than the American pint
            since the two systems are not compatible.
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="volume_fun_fact">
        The Eiffel Tower can be 15cm taller during the summer due to thermal expansion, where particles
        move more thus taking up a larger volume.
    </string>

    <string-array name="weight_facts">
        <item>
            KILOGRAM|The kilogram is the base unit of mass in the International System of Units (SI)
            (the Metric system) and is defined as being equal to the mass of the International Prototype
            of the Kilogram (IPK). The gram  1/1000th of a kilogram, was originally defined in 1795
            as the mass of one cubic centimeter of water at the melting point of water. The kilogram
            is the only SI base unit with an SI prefix as part of its name.
        </item>
        <item>
            CARAT|The carat is a unit of mass equal to 200 mg (0.2 g; 0.007055 oz) and is used
            for measuring gemstones and pearls. The current definition, sometimes known as the metric
            carat, was adopted in 1907 at the Fourth General Conference on Weights and Measures, and
            soon afterwards in many countries around the world. The word carat came from Italian carato,
            which came from Greek kerátion, meaning carob seed and potentially Arabic qīrāṭ.
        </item>
        <item>
            GRAIN|A grain is a unit of measurement of mass equal to 64.79891 milligrams. It is
            nominally based upon the mass of a single seed of a cereal. From the Bronze Age into
            the Renaissance the average masses of wheat and barley grains were part of the legal
            definition of units of mass. The grain is commonly used to measure the mass of bullets
            and propellants. In North America, the hardness of water is often measured in grains
            per US gallon (gpg) of calcium carbonate equivalents.
        </item>
        <item>
            NEWTON|The newton is the International System of Units (SI) derived unit of force. It is
            named after Sir Isaac Newton in recognition of his work on classical mechanics, specifically
            Newton\'s second law of motion, or F = ma where F is the force applied, m is the mass of the
            object receiving the force and a is the acceleration of the object. In 1946 Conférence
            Générale des Poids et Mesures (CGPM) resolution 2 standardized the unit of force in the
            MKS system of units to be the amount needed to accelerate 1 kilogram of mass at the rate
            of 1 metre per second squared. In 1948 the 9th CGPM resolution 7 adopted the name "newton"
            for this force.
        </item>
        <item>
            OUNCE|Is a unit of mass used in some systems of measurement. Ounce derives from Latin
            uncia, a unit that was one twelfth of the Roman pound (libra). Historically, in different
            parts of the world, at different points in time, and for different applications, the
            ounce (or its translation) has referred to broadly similar but different standards of mass.
            The avoirdupois ounce (defined as exactly 28.349523125 g) is widely used as part of the
            United States customary and British imperial systems whereas he troy ounce (equal to 480
            grains) is now only commonly used for the mass of precious metals such as gold.
        </item>
        <item>
            PENNYWEIGHT|is a unit of mass that is equal to 24 grains, 1⁄20 of a troy ounce, 1⁄240 of a
            troy pound, approximately 0.054857 avoirdupois ounce and exactly 1.55517384 grams. The
            pennyweight is the common weight used in the valuation and measurement of precious metals.
            Jewelers use the pennyweight in calculating the amount and cost of precious metals used in
            fabricating or casting jewellery.  Similarly, dentists and dental labs still use the
            pennyweight as the measure of precious metals in dental crowns and inlays.
        </item>
        <item>
            POUND|The pound is a unit of mass used in the imperial, United States customary and other
            systems of measurement. It is descended from the Roman libra (hence the abbreviation \"lb\");
            the name pound is a Germanic adaptation of the Latin phrase libra pondo, "a pound by weight".
            Since 1 July 1959, the international avoirdupois pound has been defined as exactly 0.45359237 kg.
            Though we\'re mostly aware of the pound\'s usage in Britain and the United States, the unit has
            a vast history that can date as far back as to the time of the Byzantinian Empire.
        </item>
        <item>
            QUARTER|The quarter is used as the name of several distinct English units based on ¼
            sizes of some base unit. In measures of weight and mass at the time of the Magna Carta,
            the quarter was ¼ ton or (originally) 500 pounds. By the time of the Norman French copies
            of the c. 1300 Assize of Weights and Measures, this had changed to 512 lbs. Today 1 quarter
            is 28 lbs.
        </item>
        <item>
            TON|The ton is a unit measure derived from the tun, the term applied to a barrel of the
            largest size. This could contain a volume between 175 and 213 imperial gallons (210 and
            256 US gal), which could weigh around 2,000 pounds (907 kg) and occupy some 60 cubic
            feet (1.7 m3) of space. In the UK the ton is defined as 2,240 pounds (1,016 kg).
            In the United States and formerly Canada a ton is defined to be 2,000 pounds.
        </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="weight_fun_fact">
        Due to gravitational effects your weight is slightly less when the Moon is directly overhead.
    </string>

</resources>
